

Maria Kuosa

I'm customer oriented and results driven sales and marketing professional with experience in key account management, sales development and content marketing. I believe that strategic planning is the key for success and actual execution gives an opportunity to see the strategy in practice.

My way of working is always to look things from customer point of view and trying to serve their needs the best possible way. I enjoy working with different customer groups, giving trainings and ensuring best practices are shared constantly. My experience at Nokia and Highlight Valaistus have provided me with skills to collaborate with numerous stakeholders and enable teams to agree on the most optimum solutions from customer perspective

I'm cooperative, efficient and vibrant person, who is open to new ideas, likes to listen and loves to learn new things.





Contact

Maria Kuosa Ylätie 6 D 02300 Espoo +358 40 580 1917 maria.k.kuosa@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ mariakuosa



Work Experience

Marketing and Sales Manager | Highlight Valaistus Oy | 4/2014 – 5/2017 I'm responsible for project sales, key account management and customer service in all project phases. I run company's marketing incl. strategic planning, budgeting and marketing communications. Achievements

- 130+ written articles in Finnish at www.highlight.fi
- 30+ newsletters based on editorial calendar (Open rate avg..3,8 %)
- Winning new sales worth over € 90k in 2016

Parental Leave and Studies | Open University | 04/2007 – 03/2014 Children 2007, 2008, 2010 and 2013. Social Policy Studies (20 cr).

Product Marketing Manager, EMEA | Nokia Oyj | 10/2006 – 7/2012 I was responsible for Forum Nokia marketing strategy and tactics in EMEA region. Achievements

Forum Nokia highly visible in EMEA events

Marketing Manager, Forum Nokia | Nokia Oyj | 11/2004 – 09/2006 | run global, fee-based developer program's marketing, web service content, administration and training. Team leader for 5 people (11/2005-9/2006). Achievements

- 300+ member companies and high customer satisfaction
- Leadership award together with my team August 2006

Program Manager, Forum Nokia | **Nokia Oyj** | **3/2003 – 10/2004** | was responsible for Advisory Council (20 developers' group) program's concept, launch and administration. I also wrote mobile apps success cases. Achievements

- 10+ proposals to improve product development
- Ensuring commitment of Nokia's senior management to the program

Project Manager, e-Marketing | Nokia Oyj | 2/2001 – 2/2003Together with team I was responsible for the planning and project management of the new e-marketing channels (web site, newsletter, extranet) and internal marketing of them. Achivements

· Significant increase in usage and knowledge of E-Channels

Marketing Planner | Dagmar Oy | 9/1999 – 1/2001

I was responsible for Dagmar's marketing, customer administration and web services projects. Achievements

- Extranet-service launch together with team
- Customer magazine concept and content renewal
- Internal award from the Extranet project in 2000.



Language Skills

Finnish native
English excellent
Swedish good
German basics
Russian basics



IT

Windows and Mac, MS Office **Design:** GIMP, Scribus, Adobe PhotoShop and

Illustrator

Other: Wordpress, MailChimp,

and Google Analytics



Education

Master of Science (Economics)
Helsinki School of Economics

1995-1999 Major: Marketing

Minors: ITP and sociology



Courses

Digital Marketing:from strategy to practice
TalentGate 08/2012 – 9/2012 **Graphic Design basics**Muurlan Opisto 9/2015



Hobbies

Family activities, golf & history



Reference

Superior 2003-2005 Tom Ojala | Asio Systems Oy +358 50 576 5056 tom.ojala@asio.fi